# Kyle Romero, Software Development Leader

Jersey City, NJ, 07311, (281) 857-9006, kgromero@gmail.com

LINKS

kgromero.com, linkedin.com/in/kyleromero/

IT Leader with 10 years as a full-stack developer and 6 years in software development management, living in the NYC Metro Area. Looking for the next opportunity to lead a development organization to success, maximize business value, and provide great user experiences. Adherent to servant leadership and continuous improvement. Open to: Manager, Senior Manager, and Director roles (In-Office, Hybrid, or Remote).

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Mar 2023 — May 2024

# Director of Software Development, Raymour & Flanigan

Jersey City, NJ (remote)

#### Leadership

- Team Size: 3 Managers (.NET Team, Oracle Team, Boomi Team), 4 Architects, 30 Developers (mix of
  internal and near/off shore resources).
- Aligned teams within internal matrixed organization (QA / Product Teams)
- Defined and executed organizational strategy, including transformational 5 year vision
- Recruited and retained skilled resources for organization, growing headcount by 10%
- Held weekly 1:1's and annual reviews with direct reports and bi-annual skip-level 1:1's with indirect reports
- Visited northeast US locations to check-in with user base (5% travel)

#### **Technical**

- Largest Initiatives: ERP Migration to NetSuite, WMS Migration to Korber, Omnichannel Sales
   Experience via E-Commerce Site, 3rd Party API Integrations (ChargeAfter, Bringg)
- Primary Tech Stack: .NET (C#, UWP, MVC API), SQL Server, Oracle DB, Azure, AWS, React, Git, PowerBI, Windows Server, Boomi, Snowflake
- Directly led change control and release management processes, leading to 50% decrease in production defect rate
- Operated as SME alongside architects (direct reports) to define and executive organizational architecture strategy. On-Call alongside architects on a rotating basis with 100% coverage

## Financial

- Forecasted and controlled organizational budget and credit card, reducing costs by 25%
- · Performed invoice review and approval process for organization, leading to 100% on-time payments
- Negotiated, reviewed, and managed development partner (near-shore / on-shore) and vendor contracts / resources, which reduced contract costs by 40%
- Coordinated with infrastructure team to monitor and control cloud and on-premises costs

Oct 2017 — Mar 2023

## Director of Operations Technology, MEARS Group

Jersey City, NJ (remote)

## Leadership

- Team Size: 4 Developers, 1 PM, 7 Offshore. 100% remote team
- Reported directly to CIO and focused on digital transformation and continuous improvement, including participating in Six Sigma and Kaizen initiatives
- Managed yearly software development internship programs on 5 separate occasions
- Traveled to U.S. locations to roll out applications (25% travel)

# Technical

## Mission-Critical Projects:

- Mission Critical SOX-compliant internally developed Revenue/Time/Equipment Field Capture solution, used by over 700 field construction crews across the US. This solution sped up the closing process by 75%
- Electron based Field Safety Capture application with online/offline capability that digitized all safety
  documentation field crews must capture
- Primary Tech Stack: .NET (C#, MVC API), SQL Server, Sqlite3, Azure / Windows Server, Javascript (React / Node / Electron), Git, PowerBI, PowerAutomate
- Functioned as technical expert on tech stack and explored and implemented new technologies such as DocuSign, 2FA, and ESRI (GIS), while ensuring all compliance and security standards are met
- Implemented and trained organization on DevOps/CICD, Agile Scrum, Kanban, GitFlow, and QA processes, which increased delivery speed by 50%
- Designated and documented all architecture and SDLC for the organization and led change management process while rolling out applications
- · Administered systems such as Azure DevOps, Sharepoint Online, Power Automate, PowerBI, and Azure

## Financial

- Forecasted and maintained organizational budget, coming out on-budget every year
- Onboarded and coordinated offshore development partner based out of India

Apr 2016 — Oct 2017	Team Lead / Senior Developer,	Worldwide Machinery	Houston, TX
•	Led internal software development team and reported to co-owner of company		
	<ul> <li>Full-stack development using .NET, MS SQL, and React which delivered mission-critical asset</li> </ul>		
	management software (desktop, mobile, and web)  • Built mobile-first SPA to enable employees to see real-time telemetrics on machinery assets		
D. and D. and			
Dec 2011 — Feb 2016	Technical Lead (IT Developer /		Houston, TX
	<ul> <li>Designated as technical lead over mission-critical third level support tool with 10k+ global users</li> <li>Full-stack development delivering 3-tier web applications using .NET, MS SQL, and JavaScript</li> <li>Gained exposure to big data (Hadoop / HP Vertica) and BI/analytics (PowerBI / Tableau)</li> <li>Led logical split and cloning of system during HP's split into HPE and HP Inc.</li> </ul>		
Aug 2007 — Dec 2011	Software / Systems Engineer, X	-Fab Texas	Lubbock, TX
	<ul> <li>Full-Stack developer specializing in .NET, MS SQL, C++, and Perle development</li> <li>Built 3-tier web applications and hardware monitoring solutions and introduced Subversion source control to company</li> </ul>		
	Deployed distributed databases and web applications in the U.S., Germany, and Malaysia.		
May 2007 — Jul 2007	Software Development Intern,	Texas Tech / X-Fab Texas	Lubbock, TX
	<ul> <li>Full-stack development internship with emphasis on C++ and .NET development</li> <li>Completed a statistical analysis application and a file format conversion program</li> </ul>		
EDUCATION			
Aug 2005 — Dec 2009	Bachelor of Science in Comput	er Engineering, Texas Tech	
C	University		Lubbock, TX
ACHIEVEMENTS	2021: Promoted to Director of Operations Technology		
	2021: Nominated to MEARS Group Innovator Team (Company Think-Tank)		
	2021: Nominated to Quanta Services Leadership Academy		
	2020: Promoted to Senior Manager of Operations Technology		
	2013: Promoted to Technical Lead (IT Developer/Engineer III)		
SKILLS	People Management	Full-Stack Development	
	Financial Management	Agile Scrum	
	System Architecture	DevOps	
TECHNOLOGIES	Processes: DevOps, CICD, Agile Scrum, Kanban, GitFlow, Matrixed Organization		
	Architectures: N-Tier, REST API, PWA, SPA, , Serverless, MVC, Event Driven,		
	Offline-First, Distributed, Microservices (Novice), Containerized/Orchestrated (Novice)		
	.NET: C#, VB.NET, ASP.NET API/MVC, Blazor, UWP, SignalR		
	JavaScript: React, Node.js, NPM, Electron, Angular, TypeScript, SvelteKit		
	Scripting: Python		
	Web: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap		
	Containerization (Novice): Docker, Kubernetes		
	DB: SQL Server, Sqlite3, Oracle		
	Cloud: Azure, AWS, Netlify		
	Servers: Windows Server, Linux (Ubuntu/Debian)		
	Tooling: Azure DevOps, GitHub, Visual Studio/VS Code, SSMS, DBeaver		
	ETL: Boomi, SSIS		
	Message Queue: Azure Service Bus		
	AI: ChatGPT, Microsoft CoPilot		
	Data Warehouse: Snowflake		
	Reporting: SSRS, PowerBI		
	Other: Sharepoint Online, PowerApps, PowerAutomate, Twilio, JWT, Swagger, C++		